A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Collected papers (Reports 011534), 1981; Horowitz, Donald L.; Beshir, Mohamed Omer, 1926-; Eleazu, Uma O.; Malwal, Bona; Nyong'o, Peter Anyang', 1945-; Okoth-Ogendo, H. W. O.; Oyovbaire, S. Egite; De Silva, Chandra Richard, 1940-; Srinivasavaradan, T. C. A., 1922-1987; Roy Burman, B. K.
  Collected papers of a workshop sponsored by the Ford Foundation's program in Public Policy and Social Organization, on structural arrangements to ease ethnic tensions. Contains: draft agenda;consulting agreements of several participants;and papers by Dona
  Structural techniques to reduce ethnic conflict;Regionalism and nation building in the Sudan;Constitutional structure and development of Nigeria;Regionalism and ethnicity in the Sudan;Politics and society in Kenya.;Ethnicity and constitutionalism in Kenya
  Cross-National Workshop on Structural Arrangements to Ease Ethnic Tensions (1981, September 20-25: Salt Lick Lodge, Kenya)
  Ethnic groups -- Cross-cultural studies; Regionalism -- Africa; Regionalism -- Sri Lanka; Regionalism -- India; Ethnic relations -- Political aspects; Minorities -- Developing countries -- Political aspects; Minorities -- Developing countries -- Social aspects
- Cross-national workshop on structural arrangements to east ethnic tensions (1981, September 20-25: Salt Lick Lodge, Kenya): Draft Agenda (Reports 011534-001) (Box 499)
- Overseas Consultant Appointment Requests: "To participate in a Ford Foundation sponsored workshop scheduled for September 20-25, 1981 on polocies and programs to reduce ethnic tension in developing countries" (Reports 011534-002) (Box 499)
- Structural techniques to reduce ethnic conflict (Reports 011534-003), 1981; Horowitz, Donald L. (Box 499)
- Regionalism and nation building in the Sudan (Reports 011534-004), 1981; Beshir, Mohamed Omer, 1926- (Box 499)
  Regionalism -- Africa; Ethnic relations -- Political aspects
- The constitutional structure and development of Nigeria (Reports 011534-005), 1981; Eleazu, Uma O. (Box 499)
- Regionalism and ethnicity in the Sudan (Reports 011534-006), 1981; Malwal, Bona (Box 499)
- Politics and society in Kenya, 1960 (Reports 011534-007), 1981; Nyong'o, Peter Anyang', 1945- (Box 500)
- Ethnicity and constitutionalism in Kenya: A general survey (Reports 011534-008), 1981; Okoth-Ogendo, H. W. O. (Box 500)
- Structural change and the problems of national cohesion - the Nigerian experience (Reports 011534-009), 1981; Oyovbaire, S. Egite (Box 500)
- Social ecology of ethnic groups, inter-ethnic relations and social action in India (Reports 011534-010), 1981; Roy Burman, B. K. (Box 500)
- Sinhala-Tamil ethnic rivalry and the new constitution of Sri Lanka (Reports 011534-011), 1981; De Silva, Chandra Richard, 1940- (Box 500)
- Constitutional and administrative institutions relevant in the context of "Ethnic" tensions in India (Reports 011534-012), undated; Srinivasavaradan, T. C. A., 1922-1987 (Box 500)
- Ford Foundation workshop, or "structural arrangements to east ethnic tensions": Impresions and suggestions (Reports 011534-013), 1981; Oyovbaire, S. Egite (Box 500)
- Foundation involvement in maternity care (Reports 011535-001), 1987; Koblinsky, Marjorie A. (Box 500)
  Notes of Koblinsky's talk to Field Office representatives at DCP annual program review meeting for FY 1988. Includes cover memorandum from Koblinsky to DCP staff.
  1, 6 leaves.
  Birth control -- Developing countries; Perinatal death -- Developing countries; Maternal health services -- Developing countries; Mothers -- Developing countries -- Mortality
- Records, May-June 1983. (Reports 011535-002), Harkavy, Oscar
  Memoranda on the population situation and Foundation activities in developing countries, prepared by representatives and program officers in the Foundation's field offices. The memoranda were requested by Oscar Harkavy, program officer in charge of popula
  Population assistance; Developing countries -- Population policy; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Festival Latino in New York: August 6-31, 1986, New York Shakespeare Festival (Reports 011536), Pottlitzer, Joanne (Box 500)
  Contains: evaluation of the 1986 Festival Latino, produced by Joseph Papp and the New York Shakespeare Festival.
  08500741
  Performing arts festivals -- New York (N.Y.); Ethnic performing arts -- United States; Hispanic American Arts; Latin Americans -- United States; New York Shakespeare Festival. Festival Latino
- Festival Latino in New York: August 1-23, 1987, New York Shakespeare Festival (Reports 011537), Pottlitzer, Joanne (Box 500)
  Contains: evaluation of the 1987 Festival Latino, produced by Joseph Papp and the New York Shakespeare Festival.
  6 leaves.
- A self-esteem proposal to reduce pregnancies among high school students: submitted to the Ford and Hewlett Foundations, January 15 (Reports 011538), 1984; Gordon, Sol, 1923-2008; Syracuse University. Institute for Family Research and Education (Box 500)
  Proposal recommends Lincoln High School, Jersey City, N.J., as project site. Includes appendices (78 l.) with copies of clippings, correspondence and charts providing supplementary information about the proposed project.
  08251185
  150 leaves.
  Teenage pregnancy -- United States; Sex instruction for youth -- United States; Sexual ethics for youth; Syracuse University. Institute for Family Research and Education
- Community energy strategies: a preliminary review (Reports 011539), 1980; Alschuler, John H. (Box 500)
  Reviews municipal energy management and conservation.
  Energy policy -- Social aspects -- United States -- Case studies; Energy conservation -- United States -- Case studies; Municipal government -- United States -- Case studies; Public utilities -- United States -- Case studies; Energy policy -- Oregon -- Portland (Or.)
- FmHA farm loan handbook, Sept. 23 (Reports 011540), 1981; Higby, Annette; Hoff, Harmon; Severens, Gene; Legal Services Corporation. Research Institute on Legal Assistance (Box 500)
  08350159
  1 leaf, 152 pages.
  Farmers -- Economic conditions -- United States; Housing -- Law and legislation -- United States; Agricultural credit -- Law and legislation -- United States; Housing, Rural -- Finance -- United States; United States. Farmers Home Administration FmHA
- Feasibility of enhancing EDP facilities at Agricultural Institute of Bogor (IPB): Bogor, Indonesia (Reports 011541), 1976; Luhukay, Joseph F. P.; Bogor Agricultural University (Box 500)
  Report is based upon a study commissioned by Ford Foundation, Jakarta, conducted during the period February 17-April 24, 1976.
  Electronic data processing -- Indonesia -- Bogor; Electronic data processing departments; Bogor Agricultural University
- Public Policy and Social Organization program, 1977 (Reports 011542), Sharpe, Richard S. (Box 500)
  Includes memorandum to PPSO committee members about grants to Public Policy training programs, 1977, and memorandum to Harold Howe II on strengthening the PPSO program, 1979.
  17, 5, 2, 1 leaves (4 items).
  Policy sciences -- Study and teaching
- The status of state work-welfare programs in 1986: Implications for welfare reform (Reports 011543), 1987; Nightingale, Demetra S.; Burbridge, Lynn Claire; Urban Institute (Box 500)
  08600994
  126, [26] leaves.
  Welfare recipients -- Employment -- Law and legislation -- United States; Public welfare -- Law and legislation -- United States; Food stamps -- United States; Aid to Families with Dependent Children AFDC; Work Incentive Program (U.S.); United States. Job Training Partnership Act JTPA
- Estimation of vital rates for Burma and their effects on the future size of the population (Reports 011544), 1978; Tin Tin Myint, Daw; Australian National University. Dept. of Demography. (Box 501)
  "A thesis submitted in partial fulfillment for the degree of Master of Arts in Demography," Department of Demography, Research School of Social Sciences, Australian National University. The M.A. in Demography Program was sponsored by the Ford Foundation.
  07750267
  176 leaves.
  Demography -- Burma; Population -- Statistics; Population forecasting -- Burma; Age distribution (Demography) -- Burma; Fertility, Human -- Burma -- Statistics; Mortality -- Burma; Australian National University. Dept. of Demography.
- Summary tables FY 1988 and comparisons with earlier years (Reports 011545), 1989; Dun, Doreen Crawford; Carmichael, William D. (William Daniel), 1929- (Box 501)
  Statistical summaries of DCP actions.
  47 leaves: principally tables and charts -- 28 cm.
  Strawberry book FY 1988
- Ford Foundation supported activities in Indonesia 1959-1967 (Reports 011546), Miller, Frank Justus (Box 501)
  Contains reports for fiscal years 1959, 1963, 1964, 1966, and 1967;detailed review of grants and grantees. Reports for 1963-1967 include cover memoranda by Frank J. Miller, representative in Jakarta.
  20 p. + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Indonesia; Technical education -- Indonesia; Economic development -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia
- Voluntary Agencies Development Assistance (V.A.D.A.): an evaluation (Reports 011547), 1987; Ng'ethe, Njuguna; Oruoch, Daniel M. (Box 501)
  08400473
  46 leaves.
  Associations, institutions, etc.; Non-governmental organizations -- Kenya; Voluntary Agencies Development Assistance (Kenya) VADA
- The voluntary sector overseas: notes from the field (Reports 011548), 1988; McCarthy, Kathleen D.; Center for the Study of Philanthropy (Box 501)
  [3] leaves, 39 pages.
  Non-governmental organizations -- Developing countries; Voluntarism -- Instruction and study -- Developing countries; Center for the Study of Philanthropy
- The Luxembourg Income Study: a proposal for the Ford Foundation (Reports 011549), 1984; Rainwater, Lee; Smeeding, Timothy M.; Rein, Martin, 1928-; Schaber, Gaston; Centre d'Etudes de Populations, de Pauvrete et de Politiques Socio-economiques (Box 501)
  08450769
  Income -- Research; Income distribution; Luxembourg Income Study (Organization); LIS Information services
- L.I.S.-C.E.P.S. working paper series: Attachments, June-July 1985. (Reports 011550), Luxembourg Income Study LIS; Centre d'Etudes de Populations, de Pauvrete et de Politiques Socio-economiques (Box 501)
  Contains: 1. An Introduction to L.I.S., by Timothy M. Smeeding, Gunther Schmauss, and Serge Allegrezza. 2. Poverty in Major Industrialized Countries, by Timothy Smeeding, Richard Hauser, Lee Rainwater and Martin Rein, and Gaston Schaber. 3. Income Distrib
  1 archives box (2.5 linear inches containing 5 items).
  Income -- Regional disparities; Income distribution; Poverty -- Research; Aged -- Economic conditions; Luxembourg Income Study LIS Information services
- Progress report from the Rural America Task Force, October 23 (Reports 011551), 1980; Hertford, Reed (Box 501)
  10 leaves.
  Agricultural productivity -- United States; Rural development -- United States; Water -- Law and legislation -- United States; Ford Foundation. Rural America Task Force
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: 1952 - February 1975 (Reports 011552) (Box 501)
  "A summary of the Ford Foundation's origin, purpose, resources and method of operation;and of its activities in Pakistan since 1952."-T.p.
  7 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
- From cold war to cultural development: the international cultural activities of the Ford Foundation, 1950-1982, 1985 Apr. (Reports 011553), McCarthy, Kathleen D. (Box 502)
  Explores some of the Foundation's overseas cultural activities;Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection
  Arts -- Finance -- Developing countries; Arts -- Finance -- India; Arts -- Finance -- Asia; Arts -- Finance -- Africa; Arts -- Finance -- Latin America; International relations and culture; Cultural property--Protection -- Developing countries; Intellectual cooperation
- The potential of cable television in Washington, D.C.: the question of multiple franchises (Reports 011554), 1971; Baer, Walter S.; Rand Corporation (Box 502)
  Cable television -- Washington (D.C.); Rand Corporation
- Five year plan for Winston Preparatory School (Reports 011555), 1984; Pendleton, William C. (Box 502)
  Learning disabled youth -- Education, Secondary -- New York (N.Y.); Winston Preparatory School (New York, N.Y.)
- Report on decentralized cotton spinning technology study, June, 1986/ prepared by Micro Industries Development Assistance Society. (Reports 011556) (Box 502)
  08450458
  155 leaves.
  Cotton manufacture -- Economic aspects -- Bangladesh; Cotton spinning -- Production standards -- Bangladesh; Micro Industries Development Assistance Society (Dhaka, Bangladesh)
- Keys to research: utilization and adoption, September 30, 1977/ by Linda Stahl for National Assessment of Educational Progress. (Reports 011557), Stahl, Linda; National Assessment of Educational Progress (Project) (Box 502)
  "A study conducted with a grant from the Ford Foundation focusing on selected aspects of agriculture, economics and health."-t.p.
  86 leaves.
  Selective dissemination of information; Research -- Finance; Research -- Evaluation; Education -- Research; National Assessment of Educational Progress (Project)
- Textos Latinoamericanos para la estimulacion del desarrollo psiquico de menores de dos anos: revision, descripcion y commentarios (Reports 011558), 1980; Lira L., Maria Isabel; Centro de Estudios de Desarrollo y Estimulación Psicosocial (Box 502)
  Contains abstracts of 21 works on child development in Latin America and the United States. The Latin American countries included are: Chile, Colombia, Guatemala, Mexico, Panama and Peru.
  237 leaves.
  Child development -- Abstracts -- Latin America; Child development -- Abstracts -- United States; Centro de Estudios de Desarrollo y Estimulación Psicosocial
- Trip report: province of Misamis Oriental and city of Cagayan de Oro, August 20-29, 1974, August 26 (Reports 011559), Simmons, Ozzie G. (Box 502)
  The trip by Ozzie Simmons-who in 1974 was a Program Officer in the Bangkok Office-was for the purpose of gathering information to determine if the Ford Foundation would develop a technical assistance program in Misamis Oriental, Philippines.
  Technical assistance -- Philippines
- An early childhood program initiative and "Work/Family initiative" Discussion papers for the March 1988 meeting of the Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs and Urban and Rural Poverty Committees. (Reports 011560) (Box 502)
  Prepared for the March 1988 meeting of the Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee and the Urban and Rural Poverty Committee of the Board of Trustees. Contains Discussion papers titled "Work/Family Initiative" and "An Early Childhood
  2 v.
  Work/family initiative;An early childhood program initiative
  Family policy; Work and family; Women -- Employment; Women -- Family relationships; Family day care; Education
- The demonstration as a strategy of change (Reports 011561), 1964; Miller, S. M. (Seymour Michael), 1922-; Rein, Martin, 1928-; Mobilization for Youth Training Institute Workshop (1964, April 30: Columbia University) (Box 502)
  79 leaves.
  Mobilization for Youth Training Institute Workshop (1964, April 30: Columbia University)
  Action research; Social service -- Citizen participation; Social service -- Finance
- Report on SACHED's "university college" project 1984? (Reports 011562), Bernstein, Alison R., 1947- (Box 502)
  "Based on a site visit November 15-30, 1984."-t.p.
  08400834
  22, [4] leaves.
  Education, Higher -- South Africa; Universities and colleges -- South Africa; Discrimination in education -- South Africa; Sached Trust
- A microeconomic analysis of rural-urban migration in Haiti (Reports 011563), 1979; Ahlers, Theodore H. (Box 503)
  07650356
  184 leaves.
  Rural-urban migration -- Haiti -- Econometric models
- Attachments, 1977-1982. (Reports 011565), Guzman, Eleanora de; Population Center Foundation. Institutional Development Program (Philippines) IDP
  Contains: Proceedings of IDP Popteam Coordinators' Conference, March 22-23, 1979;Institutional Development Program Interim Report, 1977-1979;A General Report on the IDP Consultative Review Project Covering a Period of Five Months (August-December, 1979),
  7700354
  Population research -- Philippines; Population Center Foundation. Institutional Development Program (Philippines) IDP
- Proceedings of IDP Institutional Development Program PopTeam coordinators' conference, March 22-23 (Reports 011565-001), 1979 (Box 503)
  07700354
  Population research -- Philippines; Population Center Foundation. Institutional Development Program
- Institutional Development Program interim report, 1977 (Reports 011565-002), 1979 (Box 503)
  Population research; Population Center Foundation. Institutional Development Program
- A general report on the IDP Institutional Development Program consultative review project covering a period of five months (August -December, 1979) (Reports 011565-003), Chua, Leonard A. (Box 503)
- Report on assessment workshop, Institutional Development Program Phase III, October 18-19, 1982, PCF Building (Reports 011565-004), de Guzman, Eleanora (Box 503)
- Institutional Development Program terminal report phase III (Reports 011565-005), 1982 (Box 503)
- Agenda items from the meeting of the Trustee Personnel and Administration Committee, June 22 (Reports 011566), 1977 (Box 503)
  var. pag.: attachments -- 28 cm.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Personnel management; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Salaries, etc.; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Archives; Ford Foundation
- A memorandum on teaching and research in Southeast Asian studies in Indonesia, November 11 (Reports 011567), 1969; Kartodirdjo, Sartono, 1921-2007 (Box 503)
  Teaching and research in Southeast Asian studies in Indonesia
  Education, Higher -- Research -- Indonesia
- Image of women in advertisements: A preliminary study of avenues for change (Reports 011568), 1975; Butler, Matilda; Stanford University. Institute for Communication Research; Stanford University. Center for Research on Women (Box 503)
  07450617
  Women in advertising; Sexism in mass media; Stanford University. Institute for Communication Research; Stanford University. Center for Research on Women
- A review of social science research at INCAP Institute of Nutrition of Central America and Panama with special reference to the work of the rural development unit (Reports 011569), 1977; Albert, Judith D.; Hertford, Reed; Pollitt, Ernesto (Box 503)
  Site visit team report. --T.p.
  Project to facilitate interaction among scholars concerned with research on Latin American education.
  24 p. -- 28 cm.
  Social sciences -- Research -- Central America; Rural development -- Central America; Endowments -- Central America -- Evaluation; Institute of Nutrition of Central America and Panama
- Report on the seminar on recent developments in international economic relations: held on January 5, 1977 at New Delhi under the auspices of the Ford Foundation (Reports 011570), Sood, Margaret Anne (Box 503)
  This seminar was sponsored by the Ford Foundation's New Delhi office and "was attended by a large number of individuals consisting of Indian government officials, government and university economists, public and private sector senior management staff..."
  40 leaves.
  Report
  Seminar on Recent Developments in International Economic Relations (1977: New Delhi, India) Report
- The international legal studies program of the Ford Foundation: report and recommendations, 1969 Dec. (Reports 011571), Schwartz, Murray L. (Box 503)
  Includes: 4 page memorandum to Howard Swearer from E.G. Barber with a critique of the report by Schwartz.
  38, 4 leaves.
  International law -- Study and teaching
- Consulting reports on population, November 15 (Reports 011572), 1976; Browning, Harley L.; Merrick, Thomas William; Nagel, John S. (Box 503)
  Contains consultant reports by Thomas W. Merrick and Harley L. Browning written as memoranda to Robert S. Drysdale and John Nagel;a summary of the reports in a memorandum from Nagel to Drysdale;memorandum about the reports from Barry R. Schumann to Drysda
  18, 14, 6, 1 leaves.
  Report on consulting visit in Mexico, October 26-30, 1976;Report on consulting visit in Mexico, October 24-31, 1976;Consulting reports of Harley Browning and Thomas Merrick: visit of October 24-31, 1976
  Population research -- Mexico; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Displacement: where we are (Reports 011573), 1980; Grier, George W.; Grier, Eunice S. (Box 504)
  Discusses different views of the displacement of low-income urban residents by gentrification and revitalization.
  Relocation (Housing) -- United States; Gentrification; Urban policy -- United States; Urban renewal -- United States; Grier Partnership
- Mexican politics: balance and prospects (Reports 011574), 1977; Drysdale, Robert S.; López Portillo, José (Box 504)
  59 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Political science -- Mexico; Political participation -- Mexico; Economic development -- Mexico
- Background paper for the workshop on Western water issues and rural America (Reports 011575), 1980; Frederick, Kenneth D.; Resources for the Future (Box 504)
  08090555
  Western Water Issues and Rural America (1980: Ford Foundation)
  Water-supply, Rural; Resources for the Future; Ford Foundation. Rural America Task Force
- Foundations and higher education at home and abroad: A tale of heroic efforts abandoned (Reports 011576), 1986; Sutton, Francis X. (Francis Xavier); Rockefeller Foundation; Center for the Study of Philanthropy (Box 504)
  Education, Higher -- Aims and objectives; Education, Higher -- Endowments; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Evaluation; Rockefeller Foundation; Center for the Study of Philanthropy
- Evaluating the effects of Ford Foundation support for education abroad of Third World nations, 1960-1980: a pre-proposal (Reports 011577), 1982; Myers, Robert G. (Box 504)
  Includes one-page memorandum to William Carmichael.
  1, 44 leaves.
  Educational evaluation -- Developing countries; Foreign study -- Developing countries
- New challenges for rural economic development: a final report to the Ford Foundation, June 15 (Reports 011578), 1982; Blakely, Edward J. (Edward James), 1938-; Bradshaw, Ted K.; Shapira, Philip; Leigh-Preston, Nancey; University of California, Berkeley. Institute of Urban & Regional Development; University of California, Berkeley. Rural Development Policy Project (Box 504)
  Contains 11 chapters as follows: Summary and Overview; The Changing Nature of Rural America; A Summary of Employment Trends Affecting Non-Metropolitan Areas in the United States; The Status of Women and Minorities in Non-Metropolitan America; Case Study:
  08100310;820-0955.
  [2], 29, 29, 28, 29, 14, 18, 15, 23, 43, 20, 23 pages.
  Labor supply -- United States -- Regional disparities; Rural women -- United States; Rural development -- United States; Manpower policy, Rural -- United States; Regional planning; Rural population -- United States; University of California, Berkeley. Institute of Urban & Regional Development; University of California, Berkeley. Rural Development Policy Project
- Rural America: a new public policy frontier (Reports 011579), 1983; Blakely, Edward J. (Edward James), 1938-; Bradshaw, Ted K.; University of California, Berkeley. Institute of Urban & Regional Development; University of California, Berkeley. Rural Development Policy Project (Box 504)
  This paper was prepared for the Congressional Symposium, "Agricultural Communities: The Relationship of Agriculture, Business, Industry and Government in the Rural Economy," held May 19-20, 1983 in Washington, D.C.